ANDREW MESTAS

PROGRAMMER | DEVELOPER | TUTOR

Summary

I am a curious minded individual with a mind to design and create great solutions to various problems. I love working with computers and being able to experience helping others when they have technical issues. My greatest strength is my tenacity as I will always put in 100% of myself into any task I take on. In addition, I am a very task oriented and organized person who can effectively work under pressure and make sure everyone on the team is motivated and not overwhelmed. On my spare time I like to learn new languages, exercise, swim, play music, and volunteer my time to teach others. I have tinkered in mobile design using frameworks like ionic to create a workout app with a friend of mine and I have also worked with augmented reality in the browser which is an on going project for me. I feel I am fairly proficient in html, js, and css at the moment I'm creating my own responsive web framework. My programming language set includes c++, assembly language, JavaScript, ruby, but at this point I know can pick up any language pretty quickly.

Employment

General Assembly

Jr. Web Developer Sep 2015 to Dec 2015

12 week immersive for full-stack web development. Develop and produce full stack web applications in a

deadline-oriented, fast paced environment. Technologies include Javascript, jQuery, AngularJS, Express.js,

Node.js, Ruby on Rails, CSS, HTML, and DBMS including MongoD, Postgres and Git/Github.

Wheatland & Plumas Lake School District

Sub Para-Educator Jan 2014 to Jun 2014

Yuba College

Computer Science Tutor

Aug 2014 to May 2015

-- Content Tutor --

COMSC 9A C++ Programming, COMSC 9B Data Structures, COMSC 11 Advanced C++, COMSC 2 Assembly Language, BCA 15 Business Computer Applications

-- Roving Tutor --

MATH - Elementary Math, Pre-Algebra, Geometry, Algebra, Algebra II, College Algebra, Trigonometry

Robertson Family Development Center

After School Math/English Tutor Jan 2015 to Mar 2015

Starbucks

Barista Jul 2013 to Jan 2015

Freemont Rideout Health Group

Independent I.T. Consultant

May 2014 to Aug 2014

Worked on several projects using Mirth Connect - creating, implementing, and troubleshooting Assigned to

projects involving JavaScript, HTML, and SQL Worked with Linux and Windows servers Worked with ghosting software creating and imaging PC's Worked on deployment of 149 Medication Cart

various hospital buildings Configuring network capability on various printers General hardware and

troubleshooting Helpdesk support

Fremont Rideout Health Group

T. Intern Mar 2013 to Jun 2013

Experience in office setting Shadowed Network Tech II, III, Network Security, Network Administrator,

Network Programmer on the job Experience with Help Desk Worked with ghosting software Worked on

deployment of several type of computers for various hospital buildings

Sacramento County Office of Education

AVID Tutor

2012 to 2013

 $Monitor\ the\ behavior\ of\ freshman\ and\ sophomore\ students\ in\ four\ classrooms\ Work\ and\ collaborate\ with$

teachers to encourage students Encourage critical thinking and planning Maintain records of tutorial sessions

each week

Contact

■ andrew.mestas.dev@gmail.com

Seattle, Washington

in /in/andrewmestas

andrew-mestas

Education

General Assembly

Yuba College AS Computer Science 2015 AS Natural Science 2015 Certificate Computer Science 2015

Remote Translation Office of Sacramento

California Virtual Academies

Skills

Networking

Hardware

Troubleshooting

Linu

Public Speaking

Information Technology

Microsoft Office

PowerPoint

SQL

Customer Service

Microsoft Excel

Java

C++ HTML

CSS

Software Development

Management

Team Building

Microsoft Word

JavaScript

Teaching

Training Windows

o vviiidow.

C

Assembly Language

Data Structures

jQuery

jQuery UI

Projects

Fare Start

A full stack web application using Ruby on Rails, PostgreSQL, Ruby, HTML, SASS, JavaScript, jQuery, Bootstrap, Uber API, Google Maps Javascript API, Google Maps Geocoding API, and D3.js. GitHub: https://github.com/andrew-mestas/ga-rails

Collaborative Intelligence

A full stack web application using Node.js and Express, PostgreSQL, HTML, CSS, JavaScript, jQuery, Materialize, Socket.io, and chart,js.